Friends, if I were to ask you to
name a bank that offers all services for free, the first
name that would come to your mind would be
IDFC First Bank. However, it's
true that IDFC Bank
offers all services for free, but you
should know that no bank offers
anything for free; it always
charges fees. In today's
video, I'll tell you
some things about IDFC First Bank
that you might not know. First, let me
tell you: I have three accounts with IDFC First Bank. I
use credit cards. I have a business
account with IDFC Bank and a savings
account.
I've been associated with IDFC First Bank for about two to three years.
I know this bank very well.
I was
also assigned a relationship manager position at the branch. The
purpose of making this video is not to
defame IDFC First Bank at all.
I'm simply making this video to
show you how the bank that
claims it offers all services for free actually charges
you.
IDFC First Bank is also
one such bank which
charges you some amount by telling you that everything is free.
Let's start this video
and understand
about some disadvantages of ITFC First Bank. Hello, my name is
Manish Prajapati. Welcome all of you once again to
a new video on the channel. If you have
come for the first time, please subscribe. If you
like the video, then definitely give a like.
Watch guys, you must know that in ITFC First Bank,
we do
not get a zero balance account.
We have to maintain some minimum average balance there,
basically
idfcfirstbank.com and you will understand this disadvantage when
this bank freezes your account.
Recently, when I went home,
I got a person's account opened
online in IAC Bank and after that
I came back to the city but after a few days,
that person's account was frozen by IAC Bank.
He called me and said that sir my
account has been frozen, then I said
call the helpline number. When he
called the helpline number, he was told that
you will have to go to your nearest IDFC First Bank
branch and when I
enquired about the branch  The branch
was 200 km away from that person's home. Now, tell me, the account would
n't be valid without going to the branch. The branch was 200
km away, and this became a huge problem. However, there was
money in the account, so I had to
go
200 km away. After that, the account would be valid. So, if there isn't a branch nearby, then open an account with this bank very carefully, because if the account is frozen, you'll have to go to the branch, even if it's 500 km away. Next, we'll
discuss another important point:
minimum average balance. Nowadays,
many banks
offer zero-balance accounts. Some banks
ask you to maintain a minimum average balance.
It's absolutely true that if the bank is
providing you service, you'll have to maintain a minimum
balance. However, what
we see in the bank is
n't entirely true. First,
if you go to open an account with this bank,
you'll see in bold letters
that you'll receive up to 7% interest in IDAC First Bank, and that
too
in your bank account every month. But the truth is this.
That you get interest not at 7 per cent but at 3 per cent.
If you want to
earn interest at 7 per cent in this bank, then you will have to keep an
amount above ₹1 lakh in your savings account
and there will be no fool who will
keep an amount of ₹1 lakh in his savings account because it is better to do FD than keeping money in the account. Actually,
here if you keep an amount less than 5 lakhs, then
you get interest not at 7 per cent but at
3 per cent per annum. Now
I will show you a game by which you will
understand yourself. Suppose you have
opened an account with a balance of ₹2500000 in this bank
and you have been maintaining an average balance of ₹2500000 in it and
you have
put the same ₹2500000 in FD in a zero balance account, which you can
easily get interest ranging from 7.8 per cent to 8 per cent
in FD. If you believe that
I have got interest only at 8 per cent, it is
not necessary that Kotak Bank is  Take a bank that
offers zero balance accounts, it is
common to get 7% interest on FDs these days. So
if we take ₹2500000, the
interest earned in a year will
be 0.61%. And if we keep the same ₹2500000
in our IDAC bank to maintain a minimum average
balance, then
we will get 3% interest on it, on which
our interest will be ₹5000000 in the whole year.
[Praise]. The
bank is charging you for the entire year. Now
you don't feel that it is charging you. If we
look at it monthly, then brother, you are getting ₹0.8%
every month. Here, in a way, you are
getting less interest, whatever you may consider it,
consider it a charge or your loss.
This is what is happening to you. Look, the account
is very good, if the bank is providing you service, then
brother, you will have to maintain a minimum average balance.
This is true, but if you have a
small income - you earn 2 thousand rupees or you have a
small business.  And if you've opened an account for 25,000 rupees,
it's foolish. If you have a high-profile
business or a job that earns 100,000
rupees, you can keep it because you'll
get good service. But for a normal
person,
you'll have to suffer a loss of 100,000 rupees every year. I'm
not saying the account is bad or
useless, that's your choice. But
I am telling you that those who say they get
everything for free should
understand that nothing is free. Not just
banks, no one in the world
gives you anything for free. Another thing I've personally
noticed in my two years of experience with this bank is
that their forex
transaction system is very poor.
If you receive a payment in another currency from abroad,
you can receive it on idfcbank.com
[praise] [praise]
[praise],
so my experience with this
bank is absolutely terrible. So, the
bank should increase its service. The rest is
when IDFC Bank was new
in the market.  All their credit cards used to be
free for life, but today you will see that
they have many such credit cards on
which charges are levied, like
they have two credit cards in
association with HPCL, which
give us good benefits, but they charge
Bank 99 and
all are
idfcfirstbank.com, there is banking, there is net
banking, by the way, there are many benefits in this bank,
if you open an account
then you will never face any problem, this is
true, but those who think that
EAC Bank or any other bank gives us everything for
free, then it is not so, you have
seen that if we invest this money in FD
in any bank and open a zero balance account
there, then we get ₹2000000 on this money, so
you are causing loss to yourself,
where is this income going, it is going to the bank, so
here we cannot say that the
bank is giving everything for free, the rest is your
choice, if you want to open an account in this bank then you
can definitely do it, if you liked the information then
like the video, let's
meet again  in some next video